This month we are talking about open
door generosity.
And as I introduce this topic for the
month, we want to talk about open door
generosity illustrated. And the verses
we want to read as we stand is Galatians
chapter 4 verse 1-7.
Seven amazing statements from the word
of God.
Again appreciating our leader uh our
visitors, Pastor Simon. Thanks for
introducing them and we really
appreciate uh ambassador we we
appreciate you and thank you for for
hosting uh some of the four ladies who
came from here coming to Lwanda Angola
we say thank you God bless you and our
uh visiting speaker Karibusana God bless
you and I've been hearing quite a bit of
uh feedback from some of people who have
attended the the seminars amazing and
God bless
Galatians
the Bible says what I am saying is that
as long as an heir is under age he is no
different from a slave
although he owns what
>> the whole estate
the heir is subject to guardians and
trustees until the time set by his
father. So also when we were underage,
we were in slavery under the elemental
spiritual forces of the world.
But when the set time had fully come,
God sent his son born of a woman born
under the law because to redeem those
under the law that we might receive the
adoption to sunship
because you are his sons. Because you
are his sons.
>> Because you are his sons.
>> Amen.
>> God sent the spirit of his son into our
hearts. The spirit who calls out aba
father. So you are no longer a slave.
You are no longer a slave.
>> Amen.
>> You are no longer a slave.
>> But God's child. And since you are his
child, God has made you also an heir.
>> This is God's word and God's people say,
>> "Amen."
>> We may be seated in God's presence and
God be lifted up in Jesus name.
Shall we pray? Father,
the Holy Spirit is already among us. We
have worshiped. We have prayed. We have
given. And now as we hear your voice
from the scriptures,
speak to our hearts. Minister to us.
Those in the pavilion, those here right
here in person, and those online,
minister your word. Just the word for us
today. There's a proceding word. May
that word reach us. Your servant, Pastor
Ambrose, stands here. Anoint him. are
fresh with the Holy Spirit. My God, we
say thank you because indeed we shall
come out of this place with a testimony.
We pray these things in Jesus name. And
God's people said
>> amen.
>> Amen.
Now through the month from January, uh
February, March and now April,
we have been making certain statements
concerning the open door.
The open door. Before you forget, the
Bible says Jesus says I am the door.
I am the door. John 10:7,
I am the door. This Jesus is the open
door. When the Apostle John saw the open
door in heaven, he had a voice saying,
"Come up here." And he found himself
through the open door before the throne
of God. And God showed him amazing
things in heaven. And so
in John, we talked about the open door
vision. In other words, what do you see?
Because God wants you to see something.
He wants you to see who he is. He wants
you to see what he can do. The month of
February, we talked about open door
declarations. What do you say? What do
you say? Because there are certain
things you must say that God reveals to
you. The month of March, we talked about
open door design.
How do you walk out the design that God
has for you? And now in the month of
April, we're talking about God's open
door generosity.
How do you experience God's gifts and
God's generosity that God has sent your
way? Because that door is open.
That door is open. Don't try to push a
door that is already open. Ah, it's
open. And so when we talk about
generosity, we are talking about how God
loves us. The Bible says in John 3:16,
for God so loved the world. You see that
is generosity. That's a picture of
generosity. God is a generous God. He
says, for God so loved, so loved. You
know, we have grown in a culture where
God has been pictured as a God who is
upset with us.
God who is angry with us. But let me
tell you this. When God created us in
his image and in his likeness, after he
created us, he said, "And it was very
good.
God loves you so much.
God loves you big time."
And you know, even when you misbehave,
thank you Jesus. Even when you are
clubbing yesterday, I want you to know
this
Jesus name. God does what? He loves you.
God is not coming here on Sunday to slap
you into heaven, into hell. No, God want
God loves you.
And parents, you know very well,
sometimes some of your children
exasperate you to the to the limits,
but you still love them. I'm the
firstborn of six children. And I want to
tell you this, when I was a boy, you you
are seeing me now. This is a transformed
person.
Uh when I was a boy, I exasperated my
mom thoroughly. I gave her a hard time.
I was so energetic. I was so hyper. I
could not sit still.
I used to run through the estate at that
time. We were staying in Oafa Jericho in
the land area, a very new estate at that
time. And so spaces to move were so
many. And I would take off. I would run
this way. I would run that way. By the
time I'm coming home, I have dust from
my head to the tips of my toes. Uh one
time there was a tree just next to our
house, a very big tree. And there were
times that I would play tricks on my
mom. So I would kind of disappear. I
used to disappear in many places.
At this particular time, I climbed the
tree and the tree had a very strong
branch and I would sit on it and then I
would while you're sitting on it with my
legs at the knee here, I would turn
upside down
and hold myself by my two legs and mom
is looking for me and I'm upside down
and he would walk around trying to look
for me and then I says, "Mom, Um,
I know she'd look up
Ambrose, calm down. Calm down. I'm
telling you.
Tell your tell your neighbor. Thank God
Pastor Ambrose got saved.
Oh, this is a transformed person. But
through all those episodes, I was still
my mother's son. I still my mother's
child. And my mother loved me. My mother
cared for me. And let me tell you this,
God loves you. God loves you despite
your shenanigans. God loves you in Jesus
name. To look at your neighbor, tell
your neighbor, you look very
mischievous.
But it is good you are in church today
in Jesus name.
Hallelujah.
H if some of you stood up and told us
your story stories as a child, my
friend, we would thank God that he
redeemed you.
>> Ah, he saved you.
>> But I'm telling you, this is the love of
God.
>> The Bible says God is love. So God is
generous. You know, God is generous. If
you squeeze God, love comes out. Uh this
is the love of God. And this month as we
talk about generosity, we're not just
talking about
issues of money though we'll talk about
that. We're talking about God's
character, who God is because this is
God and people are afraid of this God.
But I want you to know God is saying run
to me. One of the things that reminds me
pastor Simon, you remember the story of
the prodigal son. And even though the
prodigal son was the way he was and he
told the father give me what is mine and
I want to take the father gave him and
he went and squandered it and did all
that things he could do but when the son
was at his low moments
he remembered the generosity of the
father he said in my father's house you
know the servants eat very well and I'm
going back home and I'm going to tell my
father let me be one of your servants.
because he knew that generosity.
Hallelujah. It is that that's what woke
him up. That's what made him make up his
mind to go to his father because he knew
the father was generous. Of course,
there was a his brother who had a
completely different mindset that even
though he still was at home, he did not
understand the father's generosity to
the point where he accused the father,
you have never killed even a goat for me
and for my friends. And the father was
wondering, but all these things that are
here are yours.
Galatians the Bible says you know a
slave mentality and a son mentality are
completely the opposite that you may be
in the house as an heir but with a slave
mentality you don't enjoy what is in
that house
and thank God that God wants us to have
the mentality of the prodigal son who
came back and when he came back and the
father said hey my son was dead but now
he's alive the father embraced him the
father ran to this Jo. Hallelujah. The
father is generous with his love. It is
Christians who are not generous with
their love. It is Christians who don't
display the love of God. They are stingy
with the love of God. Hello. But I want
you to know your life is about to shift.
>> Your life is about to change.
>> Uh it is Christians who do not forgive
others. They hold grudges the whole of
their life. Let me tell you this. The
God who was so generous that he loved us
and that he forgave us is the same God
who wants us to be generous with our
forgiveness and with our love for one
another. Look at your neighbor and tell
your neighbor, "God is generous."
>> God is generous.
>> There are three statements I'm going to
make to illustrate God's generosity.
Number one,
the blessing. Tell your neighbor the
blessing. Number
two, the covenant. Tell your neighbor
the covenant.
>> And number three, the promise. Tell your
neighbor the promise.
>> We are starting with the blessing. The
blessing is what God released in Adam
and Eve during the time of creation. So
the entire human race was blessed
through Adam. Now let me read these
verses because they're right there in
the Bible. From verse 27 and 28, chapter
one of Genesis, the Bible says this.
This is the blessing that God has given
to us,
showing God's generosity to us. So God
created mankind in his own image.
In the image of God, he created them.
Male and female he created them. And
then God did what?
>> God blessed them.
God blessed them. And God said to them,
"Be fruitful and increase in number,
fill the earth, subdue it, rule over the
fish of the sea, the birds of the sky,
and over every living creature that
moves on the ground." And then verse 31,
when God had finished all he had done by
even giving the blessing. The Bible says
in verse 31
that God looked at what he had done. God
looked at what he had created and God
saw all that he had made and it was very
good and there was evening and there was
morning the sixth day
when God looks at you he is blessed I'm
saying when God looks at you he is
blessed because you are a reflection of
his blessing you're a reflection of his
glory
of course you know what happened in
chapter 3 of Genesis
The Bible says that the devil entered
the garden of Eden and something
happened that for the first time a curse
entered into the scenario of the
universe. Now let me ask you because
you're Bible students and because you
come to Parkland's Baptist Church
let me ask you after Adam and Eve sinned
who did God cuss?
Now, don't doubt your answer. Just just
by the way, just tell your neighbor
because I'll ask your neighbor what you
say. So, who who who who did God cuss in
the Garden of Eden?
Okay. I wish I could hear those answers.
Uh
so, so who did God cast?
the serpent.
What else did he cast?
>> The ground.
Adam and Eve could not be cast
because God had blessed them.
>> Now, while you're still doubting that,
let me read Numbers 23:
New King James Version says this very
quickly. Numbers 23:19.
Because I want you to know that God is
generous.
Uh God is not a man that he should
learn, nor a son of man that he should
repent.
Has he said and will he not do it? Or
has he spoken and will he not make it
good? And then the prophet said,
"Behold, I have received a command to
bless. He has blessed and I cannot
reverse it."
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "I thought I was cast.
But right now, I know I'm blessed.
>> Hallelujah.
>> And so God, this by the way, if you read
this story in chapter 23, it's a story
about two people, Balac and Balam. And
Balac paid Balam to curse the children
of Israel. But you know, Pastor Simon,
the interesting thing is that by the
time Balam was reaching the hill and he
looked down at the camp of Israel, do
you know what he saw?
You see, the camp of Israel was very
interestingly placed. In the middle of
the camp of Israel was the tabernacle
right there in the middle.
Ahead of the tabernacle on on the north
were three tribes. They were arranged
three tribes.
On the side there were three tribes. On
the right there were three tribes and
below to the south were three tribes.
Now if if you see that what Balam saw,
he saw what?
>> A cross.
How do you curse a cross? And yet a
cross one day became a curse. The Bible
says when Jesus was hung on the tree, he
became a curse for us who knew no sin
so that the blessing of Abraham may
become our blessing.
You see, God thought of redemption long
time before Jesus showed up. And in the
writing of the scriptures, God tries to
reveal his gener generosity and blessing
that he has for us because God is a God
who loves to bless. And so one of the
things he did because the devil came and
interrupted a few things that God sought
a man that God would begin to use him to
open the door of the blessing.
When God blesses, he doesn't reverse it.
And so the Bible says in Roman, not in
Romans, Genesis 12 when he picked
Abraham, this is what God said in
Genesis 12:1-3 concerning the blessing.
The Bible says this very quickly. The
Lord had said to Abraham,
note that he's Abraham, not Abraham. So
that's the first time they were
engaging. Go from your country, your
people, and your father's household to
the land I will show you. I will make
you into a great nation and then I will
do what?
>> I will bless you.
The next verse, I will make your name
great. And guess what? You will be a
blessing. And then I will bless those
who bless you. And whoever curses you, I
will curse all the people on earth will
be blessed through you. The blessing.
Tell your neighbor the blessing.
>> The blessing. This same blessing came
upon Isaac many years later. The Bible
says a time of famine, a time of
economic challenge in the earth. This is
what happened. Genesis chapter 26 verse
one, the Bible says this about Isaac, a
time of famine. Circumstances are not
are not helping. Things are just bazak.
Like pastor Simon, you are praying that
even in this time of economic challenges
that God can shift the economy of this
country.
God can shift the economy of your
pocket.
>> Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor, "You're not broke."
>> Now tell your neighbor, "I'm not broke.
>> I'm not broke.
>> I just have insufficient funds." Just
tell them that
[Laughter]
uh Genesis 26:1, the Bible said, "Now
there was a famine in the land beside
the previous famine in the Abraham's
time. And Isaac went to Aimilec, king of
the Philistines, in Gera. The Lord
appeared to Isaac and said, "Do not go
down to Egypt. Live in the land where I
tell you to live. Stay in this land for
a while, and I will be with you. And
then I will do what?
>> I will bless you. For to you and your
descendants, I will give all these lands
and will confirm the oath I saw to your
father Abraham. I will make your
descendants as numerous as the stars in
the sky. And I will give them all these
lands. And through your offspring, all
nations on earth will be what?
>> Be blessed. Fast forward that to around
verse 12. The Bible says that Isaac
planted in that season, in that time. Uh
verse 12, chapter 26.
Isaac planted crops in that land and the
same year reaped a hundfold. I'm saying
the same year 2024. I'm saying the same
year for you 2024 that God will bless
you big time and you will reap a
100fold.
Hallelujah.
Not because you worked so hard, not
because you are so clever, not because
you have amazing connections, but
because the Lord blessed you. It is
connected to the blessing. The blessing.
The blessing. The Lord is generous in
his blessing. Look at the next verse.
The Bible says the man became what? He
became rich and his wealth continue to
grow until he became very wealthy. The
Bible says uh he had so many flocks and
herds and servants that the Philistines
envied him. And envy will show up
anytime God begins to bless you.
>> Your neighbors will envy you.
They'll begin to fight you all kinds of
things. But guess what? You're blessed.
You're blessed.
In that verse, it says, if you can go
back to verse, verse 12, it says this,
Isaac planted crops in that land, the
same year reaped 100fold because
the Lord did what?
>> Blessed him. I know sometimes people
confuse this blessing and they just sit
they just think that they'll just sit
back and be blessed. Let me tell you
this. God doesn't just bless you for you
to sit down because the Bible says by
wisdom a house is built by
understanding. It is established by
knowledge. Its rooms are filled with
precious treasures. So God gives you
wisdom to know what to do with your
gifts and talents. He gives you
understanding to know how to start
something and to cause it to become
productive.
He gives you knowledge. Let me tell you
this. Ignorance
will attract scarcity in your life.
My people are destroyed for lack of
what? Of knowledge. And so, get to know
God's word. Get to know God's word.
Study the word of God. This book of the
law shall not depart out of your mouth.
Proverbs has amazing wisdom. Meditate on
it day and night that you may be careful
to do according to all that is written
in it. For then you shall make your way
prosperous, and you shall have good
success. Look at your neighbor. Tell
your neighbor, "I'm blessed."
>> I'm blessed.
>> Tell your neighbor, "Ignorance out."
>> Ignorance out.
>> Wisdom in.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Starting when?
>> Starting now.
God wants to bless you in the
marketplace.
You see, God doesn't want to just bless
you when you're in church.
When you're giving your offering and
your tithes, your your tithes and
offerings will not make you wealthy.
It is your knowledge in God that makes
you wealthy.
God is your wealth.
God is your riches.
Connect to him. Let me tell you this.
Connect to the source. Don't connect to
the resources. The resources come and
they dwindle and they go. The source is
unlift unlimited. God is a God of
abundance. Connect yourself to this God.
And that is why God told Isaac, stay in
this land. There is economic challenge.
There is so many crazy things. But do
what? Stay in this land. Trust in me.
Obey me. And for sure God blessed that
gentleman. The Bible says in the next
couple of verses, these Philistines who
envied him began to block all the wells.
He was digging the wells and they were
blocking them. They kept blocking them.
They kept blocking them. Let me tell you
this. As God begins to bless you, other
people are going to block your ways.
They're going to stop you in their
parts. But let me tell you this, like
Isaac, he needed a word because he was
getting discouraged. Pastor Simon, uh
God is blessing him. He's getting rich.
But in the process of doing that,
everybody around him is just stopping
him. Listen to the word God gave him.
Genesis 26:24.
This is what the Bible says. Because let
me tell you this, this month of uh
April, God is going to bless you.
>> I'm saying God is going to bless you.
>> Listen to what he says. That night, the
Lord appeared to him and said, "I am the
God of your father Abraham. Do not be
afraid for I am with you. I will bless
you and will increase the number of your
descendants for the sake of my servant
Abraham. And then Isaac built an altar
there and called on the name of the Lord
and there he pitched a tent and there
his servants dug a well. And you know
they dug a well and it is called the
seventh well. Uh Bashiba. That's the
seventh well. Basheba.
Basheba. B E R Uh and it is not Biba.
It is not connected to any beer. Tell
your neighbor amen.
>> Yes. Bea beer means well. She means
seven. It's where we get the soil word
sabah.
Bea the seventh well. And I want you to
know that seventh well produced so much
water. And that well has been there to
this day.
God's blessings are perpetual
and God will bless you and bless your
children's children to the third and
fourth generation
>> in Jesus name. Tell your neighbor I am
the blessed one.
>> I am the blessed one
>> in Jesus name. In Jesus name.
>> But the second word is the covenant.
Tell your neighbor the covenant.
>> Because you know sometimes God can bless
you and then you begin to worry about
what he has said and you're wondering
God have you really blessed me? And you
say God give me a sign. I need a sign.
So God made a covenant. The word
covenant means cut.
I don't know if you remember some time
back when you when you wanted when you
are together and you promising somebody
something and they were not believing
you and you wanted them to really
believe you. You said we used to say
this word but it was ini
and you know you do this
now. is God and the God who is one
and you do this. I wonder why you did
this because you know when you do this
it's like you're saying may my head be
that's not
but there was another better one. This
is this is the other one that even
children do you know they they want to
tell each other we are friends forever
this thing is going to last. So their
last finger they connect you to the next
one. a book connected to your your
neighbor. Just just put that finger and
then and then just pull it because
you're saying yes.
Now imagine
imagine God coming to Abraham and says,
"Look, I'm I've blessed you." And God
Abra says, "How how do I know you've
blessed me?" So God takes his big finger
[Music]
into Abraham's small finger and they
say, "Yes, we'll do this." But that's
not how God did it. God did a cut. There
was a cut because the word covenant
means cut.
Genesis 15. Let me go there very quickly
to illustrate the word covenant. The
Bible says this because let me tell you
this. God has made a covenant with you.
Chapter 15, Abraham has doubts about the
promises and the blessings of God. This
is what he said. Genesis
15 verse one. Okay, let me read that.
After this, the word of the Lord came to
Abraham. How? In a vision.
Do not be afraid, Abraham. I am your
shield. Amen. I am your shield. You are
very great reward. But Abraham said, now
he's talking to God. Very in a very
these these two are friends. Tell your
neighbor, you need to be friends with
God.
>> You need to be friends with God.
>> You see, so Abraham was not so scared of
God that that they could not talk.
Abraham was God's friend. God had
blessed him. H the Bible says, "But
Abraham said, sovereign Lord, what can
you give me since I remain childless and
the one who will inherit my estate?" Is
of Damascus.
And Abraham said, "You have given me no
children. So a servant in my household
will be my heir."
Then the word of the Lord came to him.
God is now speaking to him and says this
man will not be your heir but a son who
is in who is your own flesh and blood
will be your heir. So God is trying to
speak to him. Then God said fine now
let's let me show you something. He took
him outside and said you know took him
outside into the sky and and told him
look at the stars if indeed you can
count them. Then he said to him so shall
your offspring be. Abraham believed the
Lord and he credited to him as what?
Righteousness.
He also said to him, "I am the Lord who
who brought you out of the Caldans to
give you this land to take possession of
it."
But Abraham said, he's still talking to
God. He says, "Sovereign Lord, you're
giving me too much sake. Now listen, I
need something real. How can I know that
I will gain possession of it?" So the
Lord said to him, "Bring me a hifa, a
goat, and a ram, each three years old,
along with a dove, and a young pigeon."
Abraham brought all these to him. And
then God said, "What?
>> Cut them in two and arrange and arranged
the halves opposite each other." The
birds, however, he did not cut in half.
Now you need to to read the rest of the
story. But the Bible says that later God
walked between those halves.
It was him putting his finger on Abraham
and saying look just the way you have
cut these animals and I'm walking
through them and blood has been shed you
are sure you can count on my word that I
will surely fulfill my promises to you.
I am a God of covenant. And you see, one
of the words we don't uh really talk
about in this season is the covenant.
The reason why David was so bold when he
saw Goliath, this is what he said. He
said, "How can this uncircumcised
Philistine come against someone who has
been circumcised?" In other words, he
was saying this, "I have a covenant with
God.
This guy is not circumcised. He has no
covenant with God. In other words, he is
already defeated before he starts.
Let me tell you this ladies and
gentlemen, you have a covenant with God.
>> I am saying you have a covenant with
God.
>> God cut blood was shed and God said as I
have done this any enemy who fights you
fights me. Anyone who comes against you
comes against me. The battle is not
yours. The battle is the Lord's. There
was a covenant. There was a covenant.
There was a covenant. And God said, "For
sure because I've done this, I bless
you." In fact, if you read that story,
he even gave him the future of his life
many, many years ahead. And God was
saying, "As surely as you've done this
and I've done this, I will fulfill my
generosity to you."
Look at your neighbor and tell your
neighbor,
Abraham was just like us.
How do you cut a covenant and blood is
shed and the next thing you do is do
completely different?
God says this and you don't believe him
because
chapter 16 just after this had happened
Abraham and Sarah are having what we
call pillow talk.
Sarai happened not to be in that meeting
when they were doing a covenant. So she
has her own ideas. So let me read this
in the New King James Version. The Bible
says this. Now Sarai,
okay, New King James.
Now Sarai, now remember she's still
Sarai, not Sarah. Now Sarai, Abraham's
wife, had borne him no children.
And she had an Egyptian maid servant
whose name was Haga.
At night, pillow talk. Sarai said to
Abraham,
"Babe,
see now the Lord has restrained me from
bearing children.
Please go into my maid. Perhaps I shall
obtain children by her."
And without blinking,
Abraham heeded her voice. I can just
imagine Abraham saying, "Can I go now?"
My friend, somebody that God has made a
covenant with, you have totally
forgotten the covenant that has been
made. And somebody who was not in that
meeting tells you something different
and you can change.
Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, "Allah,
[Music]
And I'm telling you that blunder with
hagger has been with us to this day.
But God is a generous God
because come chapter 17,
Abraham is 99.
God has to remind him of that covenant.
Chapter 17 verse1
very quickly tell your neighbor we are
human beings
>> because you can come from church so
blessed by the time you reach the gate
something else shifts
hello you go home things are shifting
but remember the covenant tell your
neighbor remember the covenant
>> the covenant
>> yes remember the covenant you see when I
walk with this ring when I walk with
this ring I always remember the covenant
I always remember the covenant
Huh? But there are times when I'm
driving and suddenly I see a a slay
queen. I say, "Whoa, whoa."
Then I see my ring covenant, my brother.
Why are you looking so innocent?
I cut a covenant because in this ring
when I pull it out inside it is ma's
name. I'm remember ma ma
watch outu ma m.
[Music]
I remember there was something we
exchanged. Please remember what you
exchanged with God. He's a covenant
keeping God.
>> Give God a big hand.
So don't act foolishly. Some men go to
these places and they see this slequin
or something then they remove their
rings. They remove those rings just to
show that hey I'm not connected. Ladies
and gentlemen, the covenant God made
with you is cut.
>> Everlasting covenant.
>> And so in chapter 17, God has to remind
this guy. Hey, 17:1. Then God had to
change his name because the guy was not
thinking properly. Tell your neighbor,
we need reminders.
>> We need reminders.
>> Am I helping somebody here?
>> Ladies.
>> Oh, okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
When Abraham was 99 years old, the Lord
appeared to Abraham and said to him, "I
am Almighty God.
Walk before me and be blameless,
and I will make my covenant between me
and you, and will multiply you
exceedingly."
Then Abraham fell on his face. You know,
he bowed down. Uh, sorry, my screen is
gone. Then Abraham fell on his face, and
God talked with him, saying, "As for me,
behold, my covenant is with you, and you
shall be a father of many nations." Even
in that situation, God was still
generous. Tell your neighbor, even when
we blunder, God is still generous.
>> Please tell them with confidence.
So let me tell you this. I'm not asking
you to blunder. I'm telling you that God
is a covenant keeping God.
And it is this same God
who told Abraham, "This time next year,
you're going to have a child." And
Abraham left. He's 99. He laughed.
Then God now had to make a personal
visit to his house. Can you imagine how
many things God needed to encourage this
gentleman? He's a father of faith. But
let me tell you this, it took a lot from
God to straighten his brain. And so in
chapter 18, he gives him a personal
visit and he tells him, "This time next
year, you're going to have a child."
Sarah is listening. Sarah begins to
laugh. And God tells Sarah, "But why did
you laugh?" Sarah in her personality,
she says, "I did not laugh."
God says, "But you laughed." And God
said, "Guess what? This time, next year,
you shall have a child." God is a
generous God. And I'm declaring to
somebody right now in Jesus name. May
that generosity connect with you this
month.
>> Amen.
>> In Jesus name.
>> The generosity of his love. You know, I
was writing down something here
and I said that God is generous in in in
in in about eight ways and I said I'll
just share it with you. You know that
God is generous. Uh he's he's just
generous. Um now I don't know where I
put that paper but God is generous in
eight ways. He's generous in favor. He's
generous in love. He's generous in his
promises. God is what? is generous. He's
generous in salvation. You know, let me
tell you this. There are some of you who
have still not given your life to Jesus
Christ.
And yet God is still standing there
saying, "Come to me all you who labor
under heavy lad and I'll give you rest."
God is not stingy with his salvation.
God does not choose who he saves and who
he doesn't. God is saying that salvation
was catered for every human being on
this planet.
He's a generous God. Tell your neighbor,
God is a generous God.
>> God.
>> But let me tie this
giving you the last part. What was the
first statement?
>> The blessing. What is the second one?
>> What is the third one?
>> The promise.
Isaiah chapter 9 verse 6, God made the
promise of the coming Messiah
who would take the inheritance and the
riches and the wealth of heaven and
bring them to us. Now listen to what
Isaiah says in number chapter 9 verse 6
and 7.
For unto us a child is born, unto us a
son is given, and the government will be
>> upon his shoulder, and his name will be
called Wonderful Counselor, Mighty God,
Everlasting Father, the Prince of Peace.
It says, of the increase of his
government and peace, there will be no
end upon the throne of David and over
his kingdom to order it and establish it
with judgment and justice. From that
time forward, even forever, the zeal of
the Lord of hosts will perform this.
Amen.
>> So God is in heaven.
God is seeing how we are struggling. And
God is saying, "How can I bring my
treasure, my bounty to this people?" And
God says, "I'll put all that I own and
all that I have in my son Jesus Christ."
And then he said, "Jesus, go to that
earth and deposit my treasure to the
people. Show them I'm a generous God.
Show them that I love them. Show them
that I have good thoughts towards them."
No wonder when Jesus came, he said, "The
thief comes to do what?
>> To steal and kill and destroy. But I
have come that you may have life and
have it how
>> abundantly.
It is through the promise of God that he
came. By the way, when you read the book
of Galatians, especially chapter 3, it
talks about the curse and the blessing
and the blessing of Abraham. And he
talks about how Jesus Christ is the one
who has brought that blessing. But in
chapter 4, which we read, the challenge
is not in the blessing and the
generosity of God. The challenge is our
mentality. We have the mentality of
slavery instead of the mentality of
sunship.
And it is my prayer that this month as
we talk about generosity, you will shift
from that aspect of being a slave to
being a son because you are a son.
You're a child of God. Bas
you're a you're a child of God. And then
it says this in John 1:16, if I can read
that, because Jesus came born of a woman
uh born under the law, but he came
bringing God's treasure to us. In
chapter 1 verse 16 the Bible says this
and of his fullness
we have all received and grace for
grace. Let me read this in the amplified
version talks about that fullness. So
who who is the fullness
talking to you who is the fullness?
>> Jesus. So God took his generosity placed
it in Jesus. And then he says, "For out
of his fullness, the super abundance of
his grace and truth, we have all
received grace upon grace." Now, let me
tell you this, that word receive is not
passive because in English sometimes
when you say I received a call, it's
kind of passive. I received a call.
Somebody did something. I received a
call. And sometimes it is passive or you
say I received a parcel. It is at the
post office. I received a parcel. And
sometimes it is passive and no wonder at
the post office Alex there are many
parcels that are received there then
reminders are sent to you to come and do
what?
>> Collect but many people don't go to
collect and sometimes the parcels stay
there and sometimes they burn them or do
something because we do not take it
actively. The word is not a passive
word. It is an active word. And that is
why in Greek, the word receive in Greek
is the word lambano.
Tell your neighbor lambo.
>> It is very active. To illustrate that, I
illustrated with a gentleman from
western Kenya looking at a mountain of
Ugali.
Now these days they have spoiled the
activity of that mountain because these
days before you even eat the mountain
they cut the mountain into pieces and
they divide it to the children. But a
couple of years ago you did not receive
ugali like that. You saw ugali and this
gentleman from western Kenya looked at
the ugali made a prayer and said father
help me move the mountain.
And he took his hand and he hit the
mountain,
pulled it out,
squeezed it, put a hole in it,
and took the stew. That act of
is what we call lambo.
Come on, give God a big hand.
And so the ugali doesn't come to you.
You go to the ugali and you lmano it.
You receive it and you do what is
necessary and you do it again and do
what is necessary and you keep doing it
until the mountain is what? Is moved.
God is waiting for you to receive
of his fullness.
And it doesn't it doesn't get depleted.
It is always there. You don't bother
God. He has enough. He has more than
enough. Keep coming. Keep coming. He has
enough grace. He has enough love. He has
enough peace. He has enough joy. Keep
coming. Keep coming. He has all that you
need for life and godliness in Jesus
name. Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor
>> in Jesus name.
>> Take it. That is why salvation, let me
tell you this. The thief, the two
thieves on the cross, one went to hell,
the other one went to heaven because it
reached a moment when he said, "Jesus,
remember me." He lamboed his blessing.
Remember me when you come into your
kingdom. And Jesus said, "Today
you shall be with me in paradise." The
other thief died and went to hell. Let
me tell you this. There is something you
must do. There's something you must do.
Receive of his fullness this month of
generosity. Receive of his fullness.
But the Lord told me to say one more
thing before we go. Because as the God
as the as God gives to us, there is a
thief who keeps coming to steal us. They
comes to steal. The thief comes to do
what?
>> To steal, kill, and destroy. And God
told me this.
No matter what the devil has done,
you're going to recover. Amen.
>> You're going to recover everything.
>> I'm saying you're going to recover
everything in Jesus name. Pastor Simon
David um one day came home and
everything was stolen. His children, his
wives stolen, everything gone, gone,
gone. And the Bible says the men cried
until they could cry no more. And then
they got upset. They wanted to beat up
uh and stone David. But the Bible says
David encouraged himself in the Lord.
1st Samuel chapter 30 verse 6. Let me
read from that verse and then we shall
pray. The Bible says this 1st Samuel
chapter 30 um beginning with verse 6
very quickly.
Okay. David was what? Greatly distressed
because the men were talking was stoning
him. Each one was bitter in spirit
because of his sons and daughters. But
David found strength in the Lord his
God. Then David said to Abia the priest,
the son of Aheimch, bring me the effort.
Abiata brought to him and the Bible
says, "And David inquired of the Lord,
shall I pursue?" Let me read this in the
New King James because there's a word I
want to pull out from that statement. Uh
he he asked the Lord, you know, I'm a
soldier. I can revenge. I can do all
kinds of things, but God, should I
pursue them? David inquired of the Lord
saying, "Shall I pursue this troop?
Shall I overtake them? And listen to
what God said. Now, this is what I'm
telling somebody right now. And he
answered him, "Pursue,
for you shall surely overtake them and
without fail recover
in Jesus name." I'm talking to somebody
right now. You shall recover.
Go to verse 18. When they pursued, they
reached. This is verse 18. Giving you a
testimony. Verse 18.
So David recovered all that the
Amalachites had carried away, and David
rescued his two wives, and nothing of
theirs was lacking, either small or
great sons or daughters, spoil, or
anything which they had taken from them.
And David recovered all.
You shall recover all. You shall recover
all. Look at the next verse. Then David
took all the flocks and herds they had
driven before those other livestock and
said, "This is David's spoil." But do
you know what he did with that spoil? He
began to share it away. Verse 26. In
verse 26, that same chapter, the Bible
says this, I believe there's a verse 26.
Um, now when David came to Ziklag, he
sent some of the spoil to the elders of
Judah, to his friends, saying, "Here's a
present for you. Here's a present for
you. He has a present for you." And he
just gave, gave, gave. When God is
generous to you, be generous to others.
>> Hallelujah.
>> When God is generous with you, don't
hold the generosity and say, "This is
mine. It might get finished." Uh-uh. God
never gets finished.
You see, Pastor Simon,
God does not give and take away. That's
what Job used to think that he has
given, he takes. Uh-uh. God gives and
gives again.
That's the God we serve.
Hallelujah.
>> So to somebody one more time, I don't
know what you have lost, but God is
saying he's still generous. You will
recover all.
>> You will recover all. How?
Only God knows. Hallelujah.
So
tell your neighbor the pastor's finished
preaching.
Now stand on your feet.
Now which person which part of the the
message did you get?
Lambo
from all I said
that's all you got.
>> What was the first statement?
>> The blessing. The second statement.
>> The third one.
>> It is my prayer that you will understand
that God is a God of blessing.
>> And that God is a God of what? Covenant.
He remembers the covenant. Hallelujah.
>> He remembers. There's something that was
cut. He remembers. And then God has
given a promise. His promise is in his
son Jesus Christ. And I want to pray
today before you leave and even later
today. Sit somewhere. Reflect on what
I've said. And if you have never given
your life to Jesus, tell Jesus, I want
to lambo salvation today. I want to
receive your son. Because God will not
bring his son and then push him into
your heart. The Bible says, "Behold, I
stand at the door and knock." If anyone,
anyone, it doesn't matter what religion
you are, Catholic, Presbyterian,
Protestant, Muslim, Hindu, it doesn't
matter. If anyone opens that door, I
will come into him. I will eat with him
and he with me. Look at your neighbor
and tell your neighbor, you're looking
at a very generous person.
Now say it with confidence.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Amen.
>> Because the God in you is what?
>> Is generous.
Now, why don't you give God a big hand?
Just tell him thank you.
Thank you.
I'm excited. Amen.
>> I know something good is coming your
way.
>> I know something special is coming your
>> This month is your month of breakthrough
>> in Jesus name. Come on somebody better
give God a big hand. Yes.
Yes. This is your month. Come on
somebody. You better give God a big
hand.
Amen.
And remember, it's because this God
in his own willingness
has chosen to give you himself.
>> So receive him. The Bible says he came
to his own people, but his own people
did not receive him. But to those who
received them, he gave to them. May you
receive him.
>> Why don't you take a moment and just
pray? Just make a a short prayer where
you are. A prayer of dedication as you
walk into this month and just tell God,
"Thank you for being generous. Thank you
for being generous with your word. Thank
you for being generous with your
presence and with your spirit. Thank you
for being generous." And then tell the
Lord, "I receive your generosity.
I receive your generosity."
Amen.
Thank you, Jesus.
Come on, tell God thank you. Tell God
you appreciate
his blessing, the blessing, the
covenant, and the promise.
Father, thank you. Thank you for this
congregation.
Thank you for your word. Man shall not
live by bread alone, but by every word
that proceeds from the mouth of God.
Father God, these are your people. And
as I prepare to release them, may that
word that has been deposited in them
begin to grow and germinate and bear
fruit 30fold, 60fold, and 100fold. Lord,
may they be like Isaac who believed in
the covenant, who believed in the
blessing, and he planted in that year.
And that same year he harvested a hund
times and he became he became prosperous
and continued being prosperous until he
was very prosperous. Father God that is
our portion. Lord there are some people
here who are completely dealing with
scarcity dealing with issues of lack.
Unload their challenge. Some of them it
is rent issues. Some of them is school
fees. Some of them is just capital that
is not there. Some of them are in debt.
And Lord, they're just wondering after
this message, is anything going to
change? Dear Lord, I say, step into
their space.
Step into their space. Just like you
stepped into Abraham's space and
encourage him. Step into our spaces.
Because when you come in, you come in
with abundance. You come in with wisdom.
You come in with knowledge and with
understanding. And wherever you are,
ladies and gentlemen, let God come into
your space. Let God come into your
career. Let God come into your business.
Let God come into your family. Let God
come into these needs that you have
because when God steps in, let me tell
you this. You're connected to God's
eternal abundance. God loves you.
Father, thank you for hearing our
prayer. Thank you, Lord, for hearing our
prayer. Because this month, we are
geared for many testimonies. If you
believe that, you better say, "I receive
it.
>> I receive it. I take it. It is my
portion
>> and there's nothing the devil can do
about it.
Now give God a big hand and bless his
holy name. Amen.
Come on. Come on. Give God a big hand.
Yes.
Amen.
Thank you, Jesus.
Are you glad you came?
>> Yes.
>> Forget about the slick queens. I want
you to believe that God is a good God
>> and he has come your way.
>> Pastor Simon, we are excited uh that
Rebecca is going to Canada. Uh she was
in my office. We had a good prayer with
her together with her cousins. We just
thank God and she's going to great
things. You know, I was telling her
Canada in terms of the map is up there.
And Revelation chapter 4 says verse one,
"Come up here." And God has called her
to Canada and we celebrate her in Jesus
name. Amen. Amen.
So lift up your hands as I bless us.
Father, in the name that is above every
name, it is a blessing that we came to
church today. Those connecting us
online, we say thank you. Those in the
pavilion, we say thank you. And now,
Lord, I release this blessing to your
people. And I declare this to you. May
the Lord bless you. May the Lord make
his face to shine upon you. May the Lord
be gracious to you. I decree and declare
that your Monday is blessed. Your
Tuesday is blessed. Your Wednesday is
blessed. Your Thursday is blessed. Your
Friday is blessed. Saturday is blessed.
Sunday you're coming back with a
testimony in the name of Jesus Christ,
son of the living God. Amen.
Now look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor,
>> "Surely goodness,
>> Surely goodness
>> and mercy
>> shall follow you
>> all the days of your life
>> all the days of your life. and you
>> and you and you
>> you shall dwell
>> in God's goodness
>> in God's blessings
>> in God's
>> in God's favor
>> in God's generosity
>> in God's
>> and there's nothing the devil can do
about it
>> there's nothing the devil can do about
it
>> you are blessed
>> to be a blessing
>> to be
>> you're favored
>> you're favor
>> to be favorable
>> you're lifted
>> you lifted
>> to lift others up to lift others
>> in Jesus name
>> somebody better say amen Amen.
Amen.